An ironic ending, huh?
Did you get that from your precious book, too?
Everything you say comes from that book.
You have no will of your own.
That's what you're saying, right?
Don't make me repeat myself.
You really are stubborn.
It's gonna be a chore getting you out of here.
Getting me out? What are you
talking about, I suppose?
I never asked you to take me from—
Looks like you didn't expect to hear that.
Isn't everything I do written in that book?
Quit clinging to that book.
When you're talking to me,
look into my eyes, not at some book!
N-No!
It was some time ago...
when that book stopped showing my future.
Many years now.
To maintain and curate this library's knowledge
is what my contract demands, I suppose.
A library of knowledge?
She enjoyed storing up knowledge
more than anything else.
Beatrice...
You're a spirit contracted
to Echidna, aren't you?
There's nothing written in this book, yet you...
It was the last thing she told me, I suppose.
"One day, that person will
appear in the library."
My job was to wait for that day.
I've been waiting for it all this time.
But "that person" never came,
and the book didn't tell me who it would be.
Time just continued to pass, and then...
So...
I don't care if you're not "that person."
If the one who can finish me,
who can bring an end to my contract,
who can take my life, is you...
I will settle for that, I suppose.
Wh-What are you...
Are you saying you want to die?
To say I want to die is not strictly accurate.
I only want you to free me from the contract
that has bound me for eternity, I suppose.
How is that any different
from wanting to die?!
Don't even joke about wanting to die!
You can say that to other people,
but I won't let you say it to me!
That's a very selfish thing to say.
What do you know about me, I suppose?
I have lived here in accordance with
my contract for 400 long years.
Four hundred years?
It never worried me, I suppose.
I had the book.
So many times, I had dreams of
its last page being filled in.
Every time someone has laid a hand on that door,
my heart has been betrayed, I suppose.
As time went by, I realized something.
Realized what?
The reason nothing further has been written
is because that's where the owner's future ends.
You're wrong!
Why do you always jump to your
own conclusions like that?!
If you wanted someone to do something for you,
all you had to do was clearly say so!
If you'd just said you
wanted help, even I could've...
Please do something.
That's it! Just come right out and ask!
Please help me.
That's right!
If you just reach out your hand, I can—
Then...
I want you...
to kill me, I suppose.
Do you have any idea how
long I've waited for that?
Did you think I had just given up, I suppose?!
Are you saying you'll pull me out
of this darkness that's so deep,
I can't see my own outstretched
hand in front of me?!
If you say you'll do that for me,
then why... why...
Why did you leave me alone for 400 years?!
You're going to help me? Save me?
Then why didn't you do it sooner?!
My pleas for help and the
salvation I've hoped for
are wishes that have long since died away!
If you still say you want to save me...
What can I do?
Make me...
the first.
Put me first! Think of me first!
Choose me first!
Overwrite my contract! Paint it over!
Blot it all out and take me from here!
Pull me toward you! Hold me!
There's no way you can do that, I suppose.
So instead... I want you to
destroy this utter failure.
Or are you going to be "that person" for me?
If you can't, then I want you...
to kill me with your own hands, I suppose.
Spirits aren't even capable
of dying on their own.
Why must it be me?
Why, I suppose...
I know why.
The reason I entrust my end to you is...
So sorry to interrupt,
but could I become "that person" for you?
Who gave you permission to come here, I suppose?
This is my forbidden library.
No one may enter without permission.
The magic you use to isolate spaces
uses doors as its medium, does it not?
Once I knew that, all I had to
do was leave every door open.
Simple, no?
It did take a little time,
but I'm relieved to find you.
I'm so glad I managed to do it before
Maylie returned from the village.
The village? Why the village?!
Well, that's where the targets fled to,
so we've divided up the work.
Divided up?
There are more of them in the village,
but the target here is superior.
It finally gives me the opportunity
to open up a spirit and see inside.
You're protecting her?
Damn straight!
You two are so close.
How enviable. I'll send you
to meet the angels together.
Sha—
Shamac.
What do you plan to do, I suppose?
Head for the village!
It won't do any good to go there now.
Don't be stupid!
Oh, it's you two.
Whatever are you doing way out here?
That Elsa is so sloppy.
You...
Wait, you're...
I had so much fun when you
played with us that day.
Um...
Over there.
You're a mabeast user?!
I'm Maylie Portroute.
Don't call me by such an unappealing name.
The village...
What did you do to Rem and the others?!
I don't know who this "Rem" is,
but I did what I was asked to do.
The big maid and the little
maid from the mansion...
It's a shame the little one turned
out to be Petra-chan, though.
A shame? What are you...
Don't worry! She was my friend.
I made sure it was over in one
bite so she wouldn't suffer.
What's this? You want to fight me?
I hate it when my plans fall apart, you know.
My condolences, I suppose.
So I'll let my partner take care of you,
per our agreement to split up the work.
It wasn't very friendly of you to run away.
If you think shadow magic can't be
used offensively, you're very naïve.
What a surprise. I had no
idea you could do that.
How lovely.
Minya!
Have a good taste of mana arrows
of stagnant time, I suppose!
One look at an attack like
this is enough to—
Well, this was a mistake on my part.
I'm much older than you.
Now fall apart where you stand, I suppose.
Aw, I guess Elsa really was a fool.
It's your turn next.
Wha—
Hang on! She's just a child!
Child or not, an enemy is an enemy, I suppose.
But... we should get her
to tell us who sent her.
Sorry, not happening. I'll get in trouble.
Not a word out of me.
But I don't want to see you kill a kid!
You're still talking like that...
Oh, what a strange feeling.
So spirits really are different
from the rest of us on the inside.
Now I...
Now I... can finally...
Wait...
How...
Why?!
Elsa!
Is this as far as I go this time?
I don't like the look in your eyes.
Gosh, Elsa, you're so cruel.
Don't you pity him?
It's the spirit that I pity.
Imagine being sacrificed for a boy like him.
Where am I...
This isn't funny.
How much of this did you foresee, Echidna?
Subaru?
Emilia...
That's right, Subaru. It's me.
S-Sorry...
Emilia?
I was so lonely...
I was so lonely, Subaru.
You just went away and left me behind.
N-No, I didn't...
I left a letter... explaining everything.
What are you talking about?
Huh?
You don't need to make excuses.
You've come back to me, after all.
You know,
I never stopped believing...
that you'd come to me.
That if I did my best to fulfill
my task, you'd come to save me.
That's what you've always,
always done, after all.
Right?
Subaru, you know...
how you always try to touch my hair?
I'm returning the favor.
I was so scared.
I thought maybe you'd
actually gotten sick of me.
I thought you'd grown to hate me.
So I got scared and came here,
but it didn't help at all.
So I was really, truly happy when you showed up!
Stay with me forever.
As long as I have you,
I don't need anything else.
I'm sorry about everything.
I hope you feel the same way about me.
I love you, Subaru!
Hey, what's up with your left eye?
Where the hell'd you leave it?
And where's the princess?
If you mean Emilia... she said she loves me.
Huh?
She said she loves me,
and as long as she has me,
she doesn't need anything else.
You bastard...
With that cute face, in that cute voice,
so close that we could've melted together...
That's what she said.
You think this is the time for—
There's no way Emilia would say she loves me!
Like there's any chance she'd ever say that.
That she doesn't need anything else...
Never.
Wh-What are you—
If only Puck was by her side,
there's no way she would
fall all over me like that.
Someone pushed her to the point that
she had no choice but to rely on me.
So that's why there's snow everywhere?!
Drag the half-witch out here!
If ya can't do that—
Bring Emilia out here and
have her stop the snow?
I can't do that.
Why the hell not?!
Emilia's not the one who's making it snow.
It's someone else.
Someone else?!
Where is Roswaal?
Huh?
Getting an answer out of him is the last
goal I need to reach in this world.
Well, well. What an unusual
pair you two make.
You're the one making it snow in
the Sanctuary, aren't you, Roswaal?
Subaru-kun, did you hear that from me?
Hmm... I see.
I see. How unfortunate.
You're not gonna deny it?!
I could feign ignorance, but you two
clearly have some grounds for asking me this,
so I suppose I shall respect that.
Hah! Thanks a whole damn lot!
Maybe I oughta show a little
respect for your stupidity, too!
I will not allow you to insult Roswaal-sama.
This is no time for you to butt in!
It's you who needs to back off, Garf!
I don't wanna have to take this out on you.
Ram...
You truly are an excellent servant.
Ros—
I am a man of my word.
I shall offer this soul to you.
Ros...
Ram...
Ram... Ram, Ram, Ram...
Ram, Ram, Ram, Ram...
Ram! Ram!
Ram!
I cannot have you transforming here.
Now, in accordance with my vow, shall we talk,
Natsuki Subaru-kun?
Why did you kill them?
They were interfering with our discussion.
It was an awful thing to do to Ram,
but had I not created an opening,
I had little chance of defeating him.
Huh?
An unexpected reaction.
I have always known you to be the type
to blindly fly into a rage
in situations such as these.
What are you getting at, you bastard?
There's no way I'm gonna...
Let me get away with this?
Stop... Stop looking at me like that!
Who the hell are you?!
You killed them, you said all
that about the witch's cult...
You've been dodging me over and over!
Over and over...
Yes, over and over, Subaru-kun.
Very well. Since you do not understand,
I will explain it to you as if I do.
You feel no grief over their death.
You feel shock and
indignation, but no grief.
Is that not because you feel that
this is something you can undo?
You knew?
Showing you this will most likely
be the fastest way to explain.
It is not a Gospel.
Not one of those defective texts,
but the genuine article,
of which only two exist.
You have one, too?
It appears I shall not need to explain what
is in the book or who has the other one.
Judging from your expression,
I assume Beatrice succeeded in fulfilling
her dearest wish to disappear?
Her dearest wish?
That was... Dying like that
was her dearest wish?!
Is that what you're saying?!
That is what she wanted.
I envy her.
It would seem that I am incapable
of fulfilling my dearest wish.
What is it you want to do?
Why are you like this?!
I cannot say. I have made a vow of my own.
I will, however, say this.
I am constantly doing my utmost
to fulfill my dearest wish.
All of my schemes,
my inhumanity, and the assistance and
backing I offer are for that purpose.
You're following that book, too?
Is this snow in the book too, then?!
Did it tell you to make snow fall?!
Why?!
Why else?
To isolate Emilia-sama.
H-Huh?
An unseasonal snowstorm where she happens to be,
in a place with a deep connection to the witch.
Garfiel would condemn her, and the villagers
have experience with cold spells.
Emilia-sama would then be isolated
and become emotionally unstable.
Are you...
And you could never distance yourself
from her if she were to lean on you.
So that's why you did that to my letter?
Letter?
In any case, your current self cannot bring about the future indicated in the text.
If there's a discrepancy, it must be corrected.
Are you going to kill me?
Killing you would be putting
the cart before the ground dragon.
No matter what happens to you,
I need you ready to try again
at the next opportunity.
Huh?
I cannot kill you, but there
are other things I can do.
Am I wrong?
Considering the future you and I share,
this may not be a very smart way to do things.
Did I use that right?
Even after all this, you have
no mind to start over?
Roswaal...
You're talking about starting over,
but planning what you do to someone
based on the assumption that
they'll just start over is insane.
It appears our discussion is over.
Goa!
I see, I see. So this is how it ends.
The Great Rabbit?
But it's only the second day...
It is likely due to this snow.
Daphne said the Great Rabbit is
drawn to large amounts of mana...
Roswaal, I'm calling a truce for now.
We have to join up with Emilia
and get everyone outside!
And how would we do that?
Until the trial is completed, those in
the Sanctuary cannot leave the barrier.
I'm not finished yet!
You might think it can wait
until next time, but...
You seem to be mistaken about
one thing, Subaru-kun.
Perhaps you can start over, but I cannot.
My present self will end here.
But that is fine.
Another me, one who is not myself,
will be there after you start over.
So long as that me fulfills my goal
one day, it makes no difference.
That's not how any normal human thinks.
The day will come when you
truly catch up to me.
Listen to me, Subaru-kun.
There is one thing that is truly,
truly the most precious to you.
You must get rid of everything but that,
and think of nothing but protecting
that one most precious thing.
By doing that...
Roswaal!
...you can become like me.
Subaru?
It is you, Subaru!
Gosh, where have you been?
I was so worried.
Are you exhausted?
I see! All right, then.
Subaru! Subaru!
You like resting your head on my lap, right?
Subaru, are you sleepy?
Don't force it.
You're always pushing yourself too
hard for other people's sake.
It gives me mixed feelings.
I only want you to push
yourself too hard for me.
But I wouldn't like a Subaru who
never looked at anyone else.
I'm sorry. I'm so selfish, aren't I?
The Taste of Death